Sooner or later everyone does.
Meet Joe Black is a fantasy, drama, romance film directed by Martin Brest.
Bill Parrish has it all - success, wealth and power.
Days before his 65th birthday, he receives a visit from a mysterious
stranger, Joe Black, who soon reveals himself as Death.
In exchange for extra time, Bill agrees to serve as Joe's earthly guide.
But will he regret his choice when Joe unexpectedly falls in
love with Bill's beautiful daughter Susan?
Joe Black / Young Man in Coffee Shop, played by Brad Pitt.
William Parrish, played by Anthony Hopkins.
Susan Parrish, played by Claire Forlani.
Drew, played by Jake Weber.
Allison, played by Marcia Gay Harden.
Quince, played by Jeffrey Tambor.
Meet Joe Black is a 1998 American romantic fantasy drama film directed and produced by
Martin Brest, starring Brad Pitt, Anthony Hopkins, and Claire Forlani.
The screenplay was written by Bo Goldman, Kevin Wade, Ron Osborn, and Jeff Reno, and is loosely based on the 1934 film Death Takes a Holiday, which is itself based on the 1929
play Death Takes a Holiday by Walter Ferris, which is in turn an English-language adaptation of the 1924 Italian play La morte in vacanza by Alberto Casella.
Celebrating his 65th birthday, businessman and devoted family man Bill Parrish is visited by Death, who
wants to know what it is like to be human in return for giving Bill extra days of his life.
Meet Joe Black premiered at the Tokyo International Film Festival on November 8,
1998 and was released by Universal Pictures on November 13, 1998.
The film received mixed reviews from critics and grossed
$142.9 million against a $90 million budget.
The film explores themes of life and death, broken engagement, love
at first sight, fireworks, religion and supernatural.
The tone is emotional.